This episode we're talking about snake bunkers.
Every field, every air ball field, every arena field, has a snake bunker.
It might not look as straight as this snake bunker, but trust me, there's always a low crawling area for you sneaky, crawly types.
When you find the snake and you want to take the snake bunker, you want to get in here, first thing you want to do before the game, walk the field, get down to the snake level, and inspect the field.
You're looking for what position you need to be in, what large bunker you need to be behind, in order to do the most damage to the other team.
Sometimes it's not going to be the position you think it is.
You don't know until you get down here and you put your eyeball on this bunker.
When you're calling a snake, what you want to do is a modified tiger crawl--no pun intended, that's actually what it's called.
Tiger crawl is two hands, two knees, and you're just going to go like this.
It's a crawl everybody's familiar with.
But we're going to modify it because of this thing, a paintball marker that you probably don't want to let go of, and the rules do not let you just throw it in front of you and go to town.
So, it's going to be two knees, one hand, and you're just going to crawl all the way along.
Except in this bunker, it's not really an option, because you'll notice, in the tiger crawl, the position I'm in right now, I'm actually over the top of the bunker, so, which means my pack, my head, and, yeah, everything is pretty much exposed.
So the best crawl for this is a leopard crawl, which is down on your knees and down on your elbows, and you're going to crawl pretty much like that.
I am not doing that again.
One more thing to mention about crawling, and this is more of a health issue than anything else.
When you're crawling on one good hand, make sure that you don't go palm down.
It's a natural to want to do when you're crawling--you want to put your palm down like this.
The problem is you can hyper extend yourself.
You can actually blow out your wrist if you're not careful.
That being said, what I try to do when I'm crawling is I make my hand into a fist, and walk on my fist and my knees.
It doesn't always work out that way, but that's what you want to try to do.
One other thing, speaking of health issues, if you think you're going to be crawling on a particular day, and you have bad wrists or you have bad joints, take preventative measures.
I've got my wrist taped up from here to here using some medical tape.
Some of the stretchy stuff that is pretty good.
If you think you're going to do any crawling and you are afraid of blowing out your ankles or blowing out your wrists or something like that, be prepared.